# MD SAJID KAMAL

- Dream Land Residential, Kakabo Road, Birulia, Savar
- 01732-101111
- sajidkamal214@gmail.com
- https://www.linkedin.com/in/sajid-kamal



## **Career Summary:**

FMCG Brand Professional with more than 5 years of core experience in new product and brand development, digital marketing, category growth planning and margin monitoring. Data oriented with a specialization on leveraging technologies for Campaign Planning, performance monitoring and creating marketing strategies to achieve business goals.

## **Special Qualification:**

JAVA, Python, MySQL, MS Excel, Brand Development, Business Development, Campaign Management, Product Development, Digital Marketing, Market Research, Sales Operation, Food, Health & Hygiene, Beauty & Skincare.

## **Employment History:**

#### 1. Akij Bakers Ltd.

Brand Strategist & Lead, Digital Marketing (March, 2024 - Continuing)



### **Notable Achievements**

- Develop 2 new categories, Chanachur and Chocolate from scratch. From product development, conceptualize, new category planning and GTM strategy.
- Strategized, planned and developed the brand architecture of chocolate portfolio.
- Designed and executed more than 100 digital campaigns across different categories and SBUs to achieve specific business objectives.
- Lead the rebranding initiative of an English Medium School under the corporate umbrella.
- Initiate and coordinated corporate branding initiatives for Akij Insaf Group.
- Develop profitability and bottom-line dashboard for each brand.

#### Remark HB Limited 2.

Assistant Brand Manager (Deputy Assistant Director) (July, 2023 – February, 2024)



## **Notable Achievements**

- GTM Launch of Herlan Cosmetics Portfolio
- Designed and executed digital campaign to boost online sales by 60%.
- Co-ordinated NPD, production and launch of total powder project (Foundation, Loose, Compact, Eye Shadow etc.)
- Global media break for Herlan portfolio.
- Organized spot activation at various trade shows and gala events

#### Meghna Group of Industries (MGI) 3.

**Brand Executive** (July, 2022 - June, 2023)

## **Notable Achievements**

- Designed Trade Program for Noodles to boost short term sales growth by 172%
- Designed Trade Program for Snacks & Confectionery to boost short term sales growth by 158%





- Developed MGI flagship store program under which more than 50 grocery stores dedicatedly sold only MGI products.
- Strategized and helped develop a dedicated sales channel for Noodles and Snacks (PL N)
- Developed and Launched 1 Jhal Muri SKU, 2 BBQ Chanachur SKU, 3 Candy SKU, 2 Wafer SKU.
- Oversee 360-degree tactical campaign launch for Fresh Noodles.
- Successfully managed a team that developed monthly content calendar resulting in 50% increase in engagement and reaction.

#### 4. Akij Bakers Ltd.

**Brand Executive** (July, 2020 - June, 2022)

### **Notable Achievements**

- Built 3 brands from scratch (Yum, Funtastic & Fast) that have grabbed 2nd highest market share in their respective categories
- Strategized and assisted in developing short-shelf sales channel that is selling avg. 10.5 crores in 6
- Developed and launched 22 Cake SKUs, 7 Bread SKUs & 6 Bun SKUs under 3 different brands
- Assisted in developing and executing two 360-degree thematic campaigns, one 360-degree CSR campaign, 11 digital campaigns (including setting-up and developing all digital platforms)
- Devised and implemented 17 different activations (mix of spot, road, school & residential)
- Oversee product development of innovative products (4 cakes, 1 bread & 1 chips)
- Developed and Curated contents for 3 Facebook pages, 3 Instagram accounts and 1 LinkedIn page
- Successfully led a team of developers to launch the official corporate website
- Communicated and directed local and international marketing agencies to develop companywide brand architecture.
- Assisted with developing 4 different cookies biscuits; Choco-mate, Horlicks, Ovaltine & Saltice
- Prepared conclusive reports on consumer preference on Brand elements such as, corporate logo, mother brand name & logo (Bakeman's), 4 different pack designs.

#### 5. Criticalink

Trainer and Team-leader (Part-Time) (February, 2017 - December, 2019)



### **Notable Achievements**

- Trained over 700 volunteers on Emergency First-Aid Treatment.
- Organized and conducted training sessions for 4 corporate houses, 10+ medical groups, 10+ volunteer bodies, 6 Universities.
- Collected and distributed funds & materials for disaster relief such as 2017 flood, Kurail Bosti Fire etc.
- Imparted medical aid to student movement participants in 2018

## **Academic Qualification:**

Exam Title	Concentration /Major	Institute	Result	Passing Year	Dura tion
BBA	MIS and Marketing	North South University	CGPA:3.13 out of 4	2020	4
BBA	General	IBA, DU	Credit Transferred	2016	2
HSC	Science	St. Joseph Higher Secondary School	CGPA:5 out of 5	2014	2
SSC	Science	Banophool Adibashi Green Heart College	CGPA:5 out of 5	2012	-

## **Training & Certifications:**



Certification	Institute	Торіс	Year	Duration
Digital Ad Expert Certification	Aleph Group Inc.	Meta, GDN, LinkedIn, TikTok, Snapchat, X	2024	6 months
Meta Business Suite Expert	Meta Blueprint	Business & Ad Manager	2023	1 year
Google Analytics Certification	Google Digital Academy	Google Analytics 4	2023	1 year
Google Ads Certification	Google Digital Academy	Google Ads	2023	1 year
Effective Consumer Communication	Brand Practitioners Academy	Agency - Client communication	2022	3 days
First Responder Training	Criticalink	Emergency first-aid for accident victims	2017	3 months

# Reference (s):

Reference: 01

Name : Shafiqul Islam Tushar

Organization : Akij Bakers Ltd

Designation : Chief Marketing Officer
Mobile : +8801713-034033

E-Mail : tushar.abl@akijbakers.io

Relation : Professional

Reference: 02

Dr. Shamim Talukder North South University

Full-time Faculty +8801400-526654

shamim.talukder@northsouth.edu

Academic